Bouchercon mss., 1970-2019 LMC 2951
Lilly Library
Bouchercon mss.
1970-2019
Lilly Library
Anthony Boucher Memorial Mystery Convention
LMC 2951
10 Boxes
The Bouchercon mss., 1970-2019, consist of program books, badges, tote bags, and other materials associated with The Anthony Boucher Memorial Mystery Convention (Bouchercon).
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift: 2019, 2022
Historical Note
Beginning in 1970 in Santa Monica, California, the Anthony Boucher Memorial Mystery Convention (Bouchercon) is an annual mystery convention held in honor of author Anthony Boucher.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of materials related to Bouchercons, occurring annually from 1970-present. For each convention year, there is some combination of the following: souvenir programs, pocket programs, tote bags, short story anthologies, name badges, and ephemera including Anthony Award ballots, convention progress reports, menus, schedules, advertisements, and bookmarks.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Related Materials
See the Mystery Writers of America mss. and the White mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Separated Materials
Short story anthologies for the years 2014 through 2019 were separated from the collection and may be found by searching IUCAT.
Mystery fans; Detective and mystery stories; Fandom & culture; zines; Anthony Boucher Memorial Mystery Convention
- Bouchercon By Year, 1970-2019
  - Bouchercon I-VII (Materials from Len Moffatt and June Moffatt), 1970-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bouchercon VI-XII, 1975-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bouchercon XIII / San Francisco, CA, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bouchercon XIV / "Manhattan Mayhem" / New York, NY, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bouchercon XVII / Baltimore, MD, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bouchercon XIX / San Diego, CA, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bouchercon XX / Philadelphia, PA, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Raven Award awarded to Bouchercon Annual World Mystery Convention, 1989 (In Conservation)
  - Bouchercon .22 / Pasadena, CA, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bouchercon 25 / Seattle, 1994
    - Program (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "Remembering Anthony Boucher" (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Thom Walls to Mystery Mike: Program, pocket program, progress reports, notepad, etc. (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Bouchercon 26 / Nottingham, England, 1995
    - Program (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Ephemera (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Skeleton with toe tag advertisement (Box 1, Envelope 1)
  - Bouchercon 27 / St. Paul, MN, 1996
    - Program (Box 1, Folders 12-13)
    - Pocket program (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - "The Lady in the 10,000 Lakes: A Deep But Still Meaningless Collection of Shallow Short Stories" (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Ephemera (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 2 tote bags (Box 6)
  - Bouchercon 28 / Monterey, CA, 1997
    - Program (Box 1, Folders 16-17)
    - Program addenda (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Pocket program (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - "The Little Sister in Crime: A Hysterical Yet Historical Collection of Short Stories" (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Ephemera (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 2 tote bags (Box 6)
    - 2 T-shirts ("You Otter Be There") (Box 7)
  - Bouchercon 29 / Philadelphia, PA, 1998
    - Program (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Program addenda (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - "The Long Good Cry, Or I'd Rather Be In Philadelphia: A Moving Anthology of Short Stories" (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Ephemera (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Tote bag (Box 6)
  - "Mischief in the Midwest" / Milwaukee, WI, 1999
    - Program (Box 2, Folders 1-3)
    - Pocket program (Box 2, Folders 4)
    - Ephemera (Box 2, Folders 5)
    - Cow-shaped stress ball (Box 8)
    - St. Martin's Minotaur bag (Box 9)
    - T-shirt (Box 7)
  - "High Crimes" / Denver, CO, 2000
    - Program (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Pocket program (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Ephemera (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 2 water bottles (Box 8)
    - Tote bag (Box 6)
  - "A Capital Mystery" / Washington, D.C., 2001
    - Program (belonging to Chris Aldrich) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Programs (unmarked) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Pocket program (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Ephemera (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Pins with pulp art (Box 2, Envelope 1)
    - Bag with magnifying glass design (Box 9)
    - Dorothy L 9/11 T-shirt (Box 7)
  - "Longhorns of the Law" / Austin, TX, 2002
    - Program (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Pocket program (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Ephemera (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 2 large blue bags (Box 9)
    - 2 tote bags (Box 6)
    - T-shirt (Box 7)
  - "Where the Odd$ Favor Mystery" / Las Vegas, NV, 2003
    - Program (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Program addenda (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Ephemera (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - 2 large red bags (Box 9)
  - "Murder Among the Maples" / Toronto, Ontario, Canada, 2004
    - Program (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Pocket program (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Tote bag (Box 6)
    - 2 T-shirts (Box 7)
  - "Wicked Times in the Windy City" / Chicago, IL, 2005
    - Program (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Program addenda (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Ephemera (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Tote bag (Box 6)
    - T-shirt (Box 7)
  - "A Prairie Plot" / Madison, WI, 2006
    - Program (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Pocket program (belonging to Chris Aldrich) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Ephemera (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "Bearly Alive" / Anchorage, AL, 2007
    - Program (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Pocket program (in the shape of a reporter's notebook) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Ephemera (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - St. Martin's Minotaur / Mystery Writers of America bag (Box 9)
  - "Charmed to Death" / Baltimore, MD, 2008
    - Program (Box 3, Folders 5-6)
    - Pocket program (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 2 Mystery Writers of America bags (Box 9)
    - T-shirt (Box 7)
  - "Elementary, My Dear Indy!" / Indianapolis, IN, 2009
    - Program (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Pocket program (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Anthony Award nomination for Best Paperback Original presented to Julie Hyzy (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "Bouchercon by the Bay" / San Francisco, CA, 2010
    - Program (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Pocket program (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - "The Girl Who Came to Bouchercon" / St. Louis, MO, 2011
    - Program (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - "Evidence" swag bag (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - 3 Mystery Writers of America bags (Box 9)
  - "Crime Fiction Rocks!" / Cleveland, OH, 2012
    - Program (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Pocket program (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Mystery Writers of America bag (Box 9)
    - Anthony Award for Julie Hyzy, 2012 (In Conservation)
  - "A New York State of Crime" / Albany, NY, 2013
    - Program (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - 2013 pocket calendar (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - "Murder at the Beach" / Long Beach, CA, 2014
    - Program (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Pocket program (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Mystery Writers of America bag (Box 9)
  - "Murder Under the Oaks" / Raleigh, NC, 2015
    - Program (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Pocket program (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Mystery Writers of America bag (Box 9)
  - "Down in New Orleans" / New Orleans, LA, 2016
    - Program (Box 3, Folders 23-24)
    - Pocket program (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Mystery Writers of America bag (Box 9)
  - "Passport to Murder" / Toronto, Ontario, Canada, 2017
    - Program (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Pocket program (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Mystery Writers of America bag (Box 9)
  - St. Petersburg, FL, 2018
    - Program (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Program and pocket program belonging to Chris Aldrich (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Thomas & Mercer tote bag (Box 9)
  - "Denim, Diamonds, and Death" / Dallas, TX, 2019
    - Program (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Pocket program (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Ephemera (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - "Boucher: A Family Portrait" (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Banner? (Box 6)
    - Olivia Riegel crown-shaped box with skull design (Box 8)
    - Mystery Writers of America bag (Box 9)
    - Award: "For the First 50 Years of Bouchercon Fans 1969-2019" (In Conservation)
- Miscellaneous Swag, undated
  - Bookmarks, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Pins, undated: "I Got Todd Hayes Drunk! The Hollow Entourage Pass" and "Blood Games, Lee Killough" (Box 5)
  - Ruler, undated, and keychain, undated (Box 5)
- Name Badges, 1995-2019
  - Chris Aldrich
    - 1996 (Box 4)
    - 1997 (Box 4)
    - 1999 (Box 4)
    - 2001 (Box 4)
    - 2003 (Box 4)
    - 2004 (Box 5)
    - 2005 (Box 4)
    - 2006 (Box 4)
    - 2007 (Box 4)
    - 2009? (Box 5)
    - 2011 (Box 4)
    - 2013 (Box 4)
    - 2014 (Box 4)
    - Dorothy-L Mingle Police badge (Box 4)
    - Pegasus Books (Box 4)
    - Sisters in Crime, 2017 (Box 5)
    - Sisters in Crime, undated (Box 5)
    - Smashwords (Box 4)
    - Strand Magazine (Box 4)
  - Bob Marotta
    - 1995 (Box 4)
    - 1996 (Box 4)
    - 1997 (Box 4)
    - 1998 (Box 4)
    - 1999 (Box 4)
    - 2000 (Box 4)
    - 2001 (Box 4)
    - 2002 (Box 4)
    - 2003 (Box 4)
    - 2004 (Box 5)
    - 2005 (Box 4)
    - 2006 (Box 4)
    - 2008 (Box 5)
    - 2009 (Box 5)
    - 2012 (Box 4)
  - No name
    - 1999 (Box 4)
    - 2002 (Box 4)
    - Sisters in Crime, 2019 (Box 5)
    - William Morrow (Box 5)
- Audiovisual / Born Digital, 1995-2016
  - Audio cassettes
    - Eyecon '95 [Private Eye Writers of America]
      - Sue Grafton @ EyeCon, '95 (Box 5)
      - Walter Mosley @ EyeCon, '95 (Box 5)
    - Bouchercon '99, September 30-October 2, 1999
      - I Owe My Career to Peter Gunn; Ted Fitzgerald, Moderator (Box 5)
      - ~ Ellery Queen Radio Play ~ "The Adventure of the Murdered Moths" (Box 5)
    - Bouchercon 2000, September 7-10, 2000
      - Across the Pond; Natasha Cooper, Moderator (Box 5)
      - Getting Your Feet Wet; Steve Miller, Moderator (Box 5)
      - The Hidden Agenda; Julie Kaewert, Moderator (Box 5)
  - CDs
    - Bouchercon, 2011
      - Me and the Devil (Box 5)
      - Me & the Devil (Box 5)
    - Bouchercon, 2012
      - Elizabeth George (Box 5)
      - Fan GoHs Share Favorites (Box 5)
      - I Am Woman (Box 5)
      - Mystery Blogs (Box 5)
      - Pleasures + Perils of Series Sleuths (Box 5)
      - Put the Fan in Fanatic (Box 5)
    - LCC [Left Coast Crime], 2013
      - Truth or Dare (Box 5)
    - Bouchercon, 2014
      - Al Abramson (Box 5)
      - Changing Technologies, 2 Copies (Box 5)
      - Just the Facts (Box 5)
      - Make Sure Details are Correct (Box 5)
      - Technology, Science and Crime (Box 5)
    - Bouchercon, 2015
      - FAN: favorite crime, mystery & thrillers! (Box 5)
    - Bouchercon, 2016
      - Fan Guests - Jon, Ruth Jordan (Box 5)
      - Touring Stories from The Road (Box 5)
      - Quiz Show (Box 5)
- Mystery Fan Zines, 1973-1984, 2006
  - Business card: Mystery Mike, Carmel, IN (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - The Armchair Detective / Richard L. Roe, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents
    Issues
    Vol. 9, No. 4 (October 1976)
  - Attic Revivals / Bernard A. Drew, 1979-1983 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    No. 1 (1979)
    No. 2 (1980)
    1982
    1983
  - Cloak and Dagger / Jim Huang, 1977-1980 (Box 10, Folders 4-5)
    No. 3 (September 23, 1977)
    No. 4 (October 21, 1977)
    No. 6 (February 17, 1978)
    No. 7 (April 7, 1978)
    No. 8 (May 26, 1978)
    No. 9 (July 14, 1978)
    No. 10 (September 29, 1978)
    No. 11 (November 24, 1978)
    No. 12 (January 12, 1978)
    No. 13 & 14 (July 1979)
    No. 15 (August 10, 1980)
    No. 16 (September 30, 1980)
  - The Mystery Fancier / Guy M. Townsend, 1979-1984 (Box 10, Folders 6-9)
    Vol. 3, No. 1 (March/April 1979)
    Vol. 3, No. 3 (May/June 1979)
    Vol. 3, No. 4 (July/August 1979)
    Vol. 3, No. 6 (November/December 1979)
    Vol. 4, No. 1 (January/February 1980)
    Vol. 4, No. 4 (July/August 1980)
    Vol. 4, No. 6 (November/December 1980)
    Vol. 6, No. 1 (January/February 1982)
    Vol. 6, No. 2 (March/April 1982)
    Vol. 6, No. 3 (May/June 1982)
    Vol. 6, No. 4 (July/August 1982)
    Vol. 6, No. 5 (September/October 1982)
    Vol. 6, No. 6 (November/December 1982)
    Vol. 8, No. 1 (January/February 1984)
  - Mystery Readers Journal: The Journal of Mystery Readers International / Janet A. Rudolph, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Vol. 22, No. 2 (Summer 2006)
  - The Not So Private Eye / Andy Jaysnovitch, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    No. 9 (January 1982)
    No. 10
  - The Poisoned Pen / Jeffrey Meyerson, 1982-1984 (Box 10, Folders 12-13)
    Vol. 5, No. 1 (July 1982)
    Vol. 5, No. 2 (November/December 1982)
    Vol. 5, No. 3 (May/June 1983)
    Vol. 5, No. 4 (October 1983)
    Index to the Poisoned Pen (Vol. 5, 1982-1983), compiled by Dorothy U. and David H. Doerrer
    Vol. 6, No. 1 (Spring 1984)
    Unidentified loose pages
  - The Rohmer Review / Robert E. Briney, 1973-1981 (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
    No. 11 (December 1973)
    No. 12 (September 1974)
    No. 13 (August 1975)
    No. 14 (July 1976)
    No. 15 (September 1976)
    No. 16 (July 1977)
    No. 17 (August 1977)
    No. 18 (Spring/Summer 1981)
  - Spiderweb / Karen Shapiro, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    No. 3 (Summer 1982)
    No. 4 (Fall 1982)
  - The Thieftaker Journals, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    Vol. 1, No. 2 (January 1982)
    Vol. 1, No. 3 (March 1982)
    Vol. 1, No. 4 (May 1982)
    Vol. 1, No. 5 (July 1982)
    Vol. 1, No. 6 (September 1982)
    Vol. 2, No. 1 (November 1982)
    Vol. 2, No. 2 (January 1983)
    Vol. 2, No. 3 (March 1983)
    Vol. 2, No. 5 (July 1983)
    Vol. 2, No. 6 (November 1983): Brass Knuckles & Back Alleys
  - The Thorndyke File / Philip T. Asdell, 1976-1981 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    No. 1 (Spring 1976)
    No. 2 (Fall 1976)
    No. 3 (Spring 1977)
    No. 4 (Fall 1977)
    No. 11 (Spring 1981)